Guide to the Lydia Winston Malbin Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Collecting Art, 1951-1988; Series IX; (9 boxes)
  - Secondary Materials
    - List of Exhibitions Catalogs and Loans of Winston-Malbin collection (Box 65, Folder 984)
    - Partial List of Publications containing Illustrations of Works in the Winston collection, 1972 (Box 65, Folder 985)
- Projects and Activities, 1957-1988; Series X; (3 boxes)
  This series consists of files relating to to various projects and activities in which Malbin was involved.
  - LWM talks and articles, 1957-1958 (Box 66, Folder 986)
  - Detroit Institute of Arts, 1959 Nov 4 (Box 66, Folder 987)
  - Kalamazoo, 1958 Nov 11 (Box 66, Folder 988)
  - Willestead Gallery, 1960 Feb 16 (Box 66, Folder 989)
  - DIA Collectors Club, 1961 Oct 25 (Box 66, Folder 990)
  - re: Futurism, circa 1961 (Box 66, Folder 991)
  - Reflections on Art Collecting as a Creative Process, Wayne State University, 1961 Nov 29 (Box 66, Folder 992)
  - Treasures, 1962 Oct 25 (Box 66, Folder 993)
  - Art of Collecting, 1964 Feb 26 (Box 66, Folder 994)
  - Insights into art collecting, 1966 Dec 9 (Box 66, Folder 995)
  - In search of art, 1970 Jan 23 (Box 66, Folder 996)
  - At Guggenheim, 1973 Nov 29 (Box 66, Folder 997)
  - Collecting Modern Art, 1939-1974, 1974 Nov 14 (Box 66, Folder 998)
  - Paris and the 20s, 1980 Aug 8 (Box 66, Folder 999)
  - Experiences in Collecting Art, Philadelphia Museum of Art, 1980 Dec 10 (Box 66, Folder 1000)
  - Notes for talks (Box 66, Folder 1001)
  - Art & Auction article re: LWM, 1987 (Box 66, Folder 1002)
  - Letter from Cranbrook Academy of Art, 1945 (Box 66, Folder 1003)
  - Honorary Degree from Wayne State, 1961 Nov 29 (Box 66, Folder 1004-1005)
  - Wayne State activities, 1961-1965 (Box 66, Folder 1006)
  - Governors Arts Award; DIA Volunteer Award, 1986 (Box 66, Folder 1007)
  - Honors and awards, 1974, 1987 (Box 66, Folder 1008-1009)
  - Miscellaneous honors (Box 66, Folder 1010)
  - Detroit Institute of Arts
    - Miscellaneous (Box 67, Folder 1011)
    - Seminar: Looking at Modern Art, 1957 (Box 67, Folder 1012)
    - Collections Committee, 1962, 1966-1970 (Box 67, Folder 1013)
    - Friends of Modern Art, 1964 (Box 67, Folder 1014)
    - Friends of Modern Art Study Program, 1968-1969 (Box 67, Folder 1015)
    - First appointed to DIA commission, 1964 (Box 67, Folder 1016)
    - Commission: Couzijn sculpture, 1963 (Box 67, Folder 1017)
    - Calder Mobile, 1964-1965 (Box 67, Folder 1018)
    - LWM: Arts Commission, 1966-1970 (Box 67, Folder 1019)
    - Dodge Foundation Committee, 1971 (Box 67, Folder 1020)
    - Honorary Curator of Modern Art, 1973 (Box 67, Folder 1021)
    - Arts Commissions, 1974-1978 (Box 67, Folder 1022)
    - Resignation from Arts Commission, 1984 (Box 67, Folder 1023)
    - Notes to Joseph Hudson, 1982 (Box 67, Folder 1024)
    - Negatives of Winston Coll. in DIA files;Metropolitan Museum of Art (Box 67, Folder 1025)
    - LWM: Advisory member of Acquisitions Committee, 1988 (Box 67, Folder 1026)
    - Meeting with Philippe de Montibello and Herbert Ruben, 1986 (Box 67, Folder 1027)
  - LWM Appointment calendars, 1962-1969, 1970-1978 (Box 68, Folder 1028-1029)
  - LWM Travel
    - Paris, 1951, 1959 (Box 68, Folder 1030)
    - Europe, 1968, undated (Box 68, Folder 1031)
    - Portugal (Box 68, Folder 1032)
  - Archives of American Art Project (Box 68, Folder 1033)
  - Archives of American Art Interview (Box 68, Folder 1034)
  - LWM Interview with Rick Robinson (Box 68, Folder 1035)
  - Autobiographical material (Box 68, Folder 1036)
  - DIA oral history interview with Marilyn Ghausi (Box 68, Folder 1037)
  - Autobiographical material (Box 68, Folder 1038)
  - Venice Biennales: miscellaneous (Box 68, Folder 1039-1040)
  - Property of the estate of Lydia Kahn Winston Malbin (Box 68, Folder 1041)
- Other Papers, undated; Series XI; (3 boxes)
  This series consists of correspondence with artists and other material related to particular artists and art work that was previously restricted.
  Files are arranged alphabetically.
  - Albers, Josef (Box 69, Folder 1042)
  - Arp, Marguerite (Box 69, Folder 1043)
  - Calder, Alexander (Box 69, Folder 1044)
  - Callery, Mary (Box 69, Folder 1045)
  - Chong Bae Park (Box 69, Folder 1046)
  - Christos Capralos (Box 69, Folder 1047)
  - Consagra, Pietro (Box 69, Folder 1048)
  - Dorazio, Piero (Box 69, Folder 1049)
  - Downing, Joe (Box 69, Folder 1050)
  - Dubuffet, Jean (Box 69, Folder 1051)
  - Duchamp, Marcel (Box 69, Folder 1052)
  - Feeley, Paul (Box 69, Folder 1053)
  - Fisher, Lindsay (Box 69, Folder 1054)
  - Fredenthal, Ruth Ann (Box 69, Folder 1055)
  - Freeland, Bill (Box 69, Folder 1056)
  - Gosling, Enid (Box 69, Folder 1057)
  - Guggenheim, Peggy (Box 69, Folder 1058)
  - Hamilton, Richard (Box 69, Folder 1059)
  - Helion, Pegeen (Box 69, Folder 1060)
  - Hoflehner, Rudolf (Box 69, Folder 1061)
  - Honegger, G. (Box 69, Folder 1062)
  - Indiana, Robert (Box 69, Folder 1063)
  - Jones, E. Powis (Box 69, Folder 1064)
  - Kulak, Gary (Box 69, Folder 1065)
  - Linn, Judith (Box 69, Folder 1066)
  - Longo, Vincent (Box 69, Folder 1067)
  - Macdonald-Wright, Stanton (Box 69, Folder 1068)
  - Mondrian, Piet (Box 69, Folder 1069)
  - Moore, Tony (Box 69, Folder 1070)
  - Motherwell, Helen (Box 69, Folder 1071)
  - Nakian, Rueben (Box 69, Folder 1072)
  - Nevelson, Louise (Box 69, Folder 1073)
  - Noland, Kenneth (Box 69, Folder 1074)
  - Packard, Daniel (Box 69, Folder 1075)
  - Pevsner, Antoine (Box 69, Folder 1076)
  - Robinson, Sally (Box 69, Folder 1077)
  - Seuphor, Michel (Box 69, Folder 1078)
  - Severini, Gino (Box 69, Folder 1079)
  - Smith, Kimber (Box 69, Folder 1080)
  - Teng Beng Chew (Box 69, Folder 1081)
  - Winston, Harry and Lydia;"The Picasso Tale (Tail) and Brancusi Amour a L"Atelier" (Box 69, Folder 1082)
  - Exposizioni Futuriste, 1912-1919 (Box 70, Folder 1083)
  - RE: Importation of Boccioni's "Bottle in Space" (Box 70, Folder 1084)
  - Customs declaration for Severini's "Dancer by the Sea" (Box 71, Folder 1085)
  - Miscellaneous / Fragile (Box 71, Folder 1086)
  - Greetings (Box 71, Folder 1087-1088)
  - Paul Rudolf drawing (Box 71, Folder 1089)
  - Alleged Turner drawing from Albert Kahn Collection (Box 71, Folder 1090)
  - The Graphic Work of Umberto Boccioni, by Joshua Taylor [annotated by LWM] (Box 71, Folder 1091)
  - Greetings: Miscellaneous (Box 71, Folder 1092)
  - LWM: Futurist article for Aujord'hui (Box 71, Folder 1093)
- Albert Kahn Papers, undated; Series XII; (1 box)
  This series consists of the Albert Kahn Papers. Malbin had interspersed materials regarding her late father and the works of art she inherited from him throughout her papers. It was decided to separate this material and create its own series for the following reasons:1) It would facilitate the work of the scholar particularly concerned with Kahn or the works he collected; 2) Malbin always kept the works she had inherited from her father separate from the works she collected herself. In the Birmingham, Michigan home she shared with Henry L. Winston, these works were displayed in the dining room. In her New York City apartment, they were hung in her bedroom; 3) The differences between Kahn's collection and Malbin's were so great that to come upon materials relating to one of his paintings in the midst of files referring to Malbin's was positively jarring!
  - "Bits from S. Zeno, Verona" (pencil on paper), c. 1891 (Box 72, Folder 1094)
  - "Capitals Maison Allemand, Bourges" (pencil on paper) (Box 72, Folder 1095)
  - "Choir Rail and Steps in S. Maria d'Miracole, Venice" (ink and pencil on paper), c. 1891 (Box 72, Folder 1096)
  - "Church and English Landscape", c. 1891 (Box 72, Folder 1097)
  - "Design for Iron Work, S.Kensington Museum" (pencil on paper), 1920 (Box 72, Folder 1098)
  - "Door from House Rouen, Cluny Paris" (pencil & brown ink on paper), 1891 (Box 72, Folder 1099)
  - "Ducal Palace and St. Marks", c. 1891 (Box 72, Folder 1100)
  - "S.Fosca" (pencil on paper), c.1891 (Box 72, Folder 1101)
  - Fragment of a study, Location Unidentified (ink on tracing paper) c.1891 (Box 72, Folder 1102)
  - "Gondola with Santa Maria Maggiore" (ink and pencil on paper), c.1891 (Box 72, Folder 1103)
  - "In Dei Miracoli, Venice" (pencil on paper), 1891 (Box 72, Folder 1104)
  - "Joselin" (pencil on paper), [1891?] (Box 72, Folder 1105)
  - "Maison Dite de Diane de Poitiers" (pencil on paper) 1891 (Box 72, Folder 1106)
  - "Noyen" (pencil on paper), c.1891 (Box 72, Folder 1107)
  - "Plan of Choir Church, Mont St. Michel" (pencil on paper), 1891 (Box 72, Folder 1108)
  - "Rooftops on Shoreline" (pencil on paper), 1891 (Box 72, Folder 1109)
  - "Sketch made in Europe while on scholarship..." (Box 72, Folder 1110)
  - "St. Germain des Pres" (pencil on paper), 1930;(after the original of 1891) (Box 72, Folder 1111)
  - "San Secondino, Troia", 1891 (Box 72, Folder 1112)
  - "This is Venice" (pencil on paper), 1891 (Box 72, Folder 1113)
  - "Tower" (red chalk on paper) c.1891 (Box 72, Folder 1114)
  - Untitled [Details and measurements of architectural motifs] (pencil on paper, recto and verso), c.1891 (Box 72, Folder 1115)
  - Untitled [Gothic Tower] (pencil on paper), c.1891 (Box 72, Folder 1116)
  - Untitled [Rubbing of a floor design] (pencil on gray paper), c.1891 (Box 72, Folder 1117)
  - Untitled [rubbing of floor design] (graphite on paper), c.1891 (Box 72, Folder 1118)
  - Untitled [Rubbing of floor of Sistine Chapel] (crayon on paper), c.1891 (Box 72, Folder 1119)
  - Works from the Albert Kahn Collection
    - Bacon, Henry
      - "A Fountain" (Box 72, Folder 1120)
    - Corot (Box 72, Folder 1121)
    - Degas, Edgar
      - "Dancer Tying her Slipper" (Box 72, Folder 1122)
    - Delacroix, Eugene
      - "Figures" (Box 72, Folder 1123)
      - "Male Classical Figure" (Box 72, Folder 1124)
    - Jonkind, Johan
      - "Moonlight" (Box 72, Folder 1125)
    - Kauffmann, Angelica
      - "Diana and the Nymphs" (Box 72, Folder 1126)
    - Matisse, Henri
      - Poster (Box 72, Folder 1127)
      - Illustration from "Pasiphae Chand de Minos" (Box 72, Folder 1128)
    - Monticelli, Adolph
      - "In the Park" (Box 73, Folder 1129)
    - Monet, Claude
      - "Waterlilies" or "Nymphomaniacs" (Box 73, Folder 1130-1131)
  - Collection original values, 2 (Box 73, Folder 1132-1133)
  - Collection concerning sales of prints (Box 73, Folder 1134)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 73, Folder 1135)
  - Ford Motor Company Edgewater Assembly Plant, designed by Albert Kahn, National Register of Historic Places Nomination, 1983 (Box 73, Folder 1136)
  - LWM Correspondence with James C. A. Thompson regarding Albert Kahn (Box 73, Folder 1136)
  - Insurance/Drawings, 1966 (Box 73, Folder 1137)
- Lydia Winston Malbin Papers Addition, 1938-1997; Series XIII; (25 boxes)
  This series consists of scrapbooks, material relating to the Umberto Boccioni works in the Malbin collection, photographs, card files, and other papers that were added to the manuscript collection at various times after it was initially processed by the Yale University Art Gallery.
  Material is arranged largely by format.
  - Scrapbook, "A Story (or an Autobiography) Concerning a Collector of Modern Art (Futurism) Expressed Through Documents"
    - Volume "0", "Beginnings of Collecting 20th Century on a National and European Level", 1938-1975, 1987 (Box 74, Folder 1138-1142)
      Scrapbook contains clippings; photographs; correspondence from Alfred Stieglitz, Rose Fried, Peggy Guggenehim, Alfred Barr, Willem Sandberg; catalogs; post cards; invoice; agreement with Brancusi for purchase of "Blond Negress"; laid in: transcript of an interview with LWM.
    - Volume I, Part I. Futurism and Part II. Life of Umberto Boccioni, 1959-1982 (Box 75, Folder 1143-1148)
      Scrapbook contains catalogs, clippings, excerpts, photographs, writings, autographed menu; correspondence from Peter Selz, Joshua Taylor, J. Carter Brown, Anne d'Harnoncourt, Anne Coffin Hanson; extensive correspondence with Marianne Martin; photographs of works of art by Boccioni, the artist, and his tomb; letters from Boccioni's sister.
    - Volume II, Boccioni, Drawings and Prints, Painting, & Sculptures, 1956-1972 (Box 76, Folder 1149-1154)
      Scrapbook contains correspondence from Alexander and Lydia Dorner, James Speyer, Alfred Barr, Joshua Taylor, A. Hyatt Mayor, Benedetta Marinetti; catalogs; clippings; chronology of exhibitions; photographs; notes from trip to Rome in 1958.
    - Volume III, Early Futurist Artists, 1951-1982 (Box 77, Folder 1155-1159)
      Scrapbook contains clippings; photographs; correspondence from Margaret Barr, Gino Severini, Benedetta Marinetti; a "Severini doodle"; drawing by Giacomo Balla.
  - Umberto Boccioni Works from the Winston-Malbin Collection
    See also Card Files, Box 92
    This material may possibly have been compiled by the Metropolitan Museum of Art.
    - Notebook, Boccioni Prints, circa 1985 (Box 78, Folder 1160)
    - Notebook, Boccioni Drawings & Prints, circa 1984 (Box 78, Folder 1161-1165)
    - Negatives, circa 1983 (Box 79, Folder 1166-1175)
  - Photographs
    - "Exhibitions / Art World", Art Work
      Removed from slide carousels by YUAG and put into binders; removed from binders by BRBL staff.
      - Group 1, Exhibitions A, 1957-1974 (Box 80, Folder 1176)
      - Group 2, Exhibitions A2, 1957-1974 (Box 80, Folder 1177)
      - Group 3, Exhibitions B, 1957-1974 (Box 80, Folder 1178)
      - Group 4, Art World, Series B, 1951-1969 (Box 80, Folder 1179)
      - Group 5, Art World, Sreies C, 1952-1976 (Box 80, Folder 1180)
      - Group 6, Malbin Visit to London and Paris, 1975 (Box 80, Folder 1181)
      - Group 7, Miscellaneous, undated (Box 80, Folder 1182)
    - Art Work, Black & White Negatives and Color Transparencies
      - "A"-"B", undated (Box 80, Folder 1183-1184)
      - "C"-"L", undated (Box 81, Folder 1185-1191)
      - "M"-"Z", undated (Box 82, Folder 1192-1197)
    - Art Work, Negatives and Transparencies (8 x 10), undated (Box 83, Folder 1198-1203)
    - Loose Slides, Negatives and Transparencies, undated (Box 84, Folder 1204-1208)
    - Loose Slides, Negatives and Transparencies, undated (Box 85, Folder 1209-1213)
    - Slides (from Slide Box 1 and 2), undated (Box 86)
    - Descriptions from/of Slide Box 1, undated (Box 87, Folder 1214-1215)
    - Descriptions from/of Slide Box 2, undated (Box 87, Folder 1216-1217)
    - Loose Slides, undated (Box 87, Folder 1218-1222)
    - Loose Negatives, undated (Box 87, Folder 1223)
  - Other Papers
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1974-1984 (Box 88, Folder 1224)
    - Personal Photographs, undated (Box 88, Folder 1225)
    - Installation Photographs, 1978-1979 (Box 88, Folder 1226)
    - Material pertaining to the Winston Collection in the Archives of American Art?, circa 1981-1983 (Box 88, Folder 1227-1230)
    - Catalogs, 1951-1972 (Box 88, Folder 1231-1233)
    - Publications, 1958 (Box 89, Folder 1234)
    - Clippings, undated (Box 89, Folder 1235)
    - Videocassettes, "Conversations on Pictorial Space", 1997 February 8 (Box 89, Folder 1236-1238)
  - Card Files
    - "Paintings, Sculpture, Watercolor, + Collage" [removed from metal box, drawer #1], undated (Box 90)
    - "Graphics, Drawings, Multiples, Portfolios, Photographs, Letters, Illustrators" [removed from metal box, drawer #2], undated (Box 91)
    - "Boccioni Drawings + Prints" [removed from metal box, drawer #3], undated (Box 92)
    - "Affiche, Greetings" [removed from metal box, drawer #4], undated (Box 92)
    - "Affiche, Greetings" [removed from metal box, drawer #4], undated (Box 93)
    - Artists's Bibliography, undated (Box 94)
    - Artists's Bibliography, undated (Box 95)
    - Artists's Bibliography, undated (Box 96)
    - Artists's Bibliography (Box 97)
    - Artists's Bibliography (Box 98)
- Oversize
  - Futurist Manifestos and Lacerba, circa 1913-1977; 2 (Box 99)
  - "Futurism: A Modern Focus", Guggenheim Exhibit, Scrapbook, 1973-1974 (Box 100)